MICHAEL WHALON

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Michael.Whalon.cs@gmail.com 📞 804-334-3720 in michael-whalon/ 🖸 https://github.com/MichaelWhalonCS

SUMMARY

I'm a motivated and reliable developer who looks for ways to contribute or lead. I served in the United States Marine Corps as an Air Support Net Operator where I safely controlled multi million dollar aircraft in three different countries. That attention to detail brought me to start my own digital logistics business where the use of technology was paramount. I was inspired to transition to a career in software development after automating some spreadsheet processes with Python to make my logistics business more efficient.

SKILLS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT: Python, Django, JavaScript, React, PostGreSQL, Wordpress, Elementor

EMPLOYMENT

Sergeant Whalon Sales LLC., Owner, Morehead City, North Carolina, United States

Sept. 2018 - Current

- •Founded and operated a digital retail business with a peak revenue of over 150k/year.
- •Hired and managed a team of 5 virtual assistants.
- •Self taught and used Python and OpenPyxl to streamline processing of Excel Spreadsheets to save 10+ hours of weekly manual analysis.
- •Established productivity metrics and standard operating procedures.

LCSI Webhosting, Support Engineer, Port Charlotte, Florida, United States

Dec. 2019 - June 2020

- Maintained the security and SEO rankings of 10 small business websites using Wordpress and Elementor.
- Conducted online review management for 5 local medical practices using ReviewLead.
- Led HIPAA seminars for all employees of 3 physician's offices in order to improve compliance with federal law and avoid fines.

Sales With David LLC., Retail Sales Manager / Digital Marketing VP, Emerald Isle, North Carolina, United States

Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- Managed Retail Storefront inventory worth over \$20k.
- Created and promoted local monthly Box Bonanza event through Facebook and Instagram Ads to create 10k+ revenue from merchandise which would otherwise have been destroyed.
- Analyzed large scale liquidation manifests for profitability based on Amazon sales data.

United States Marine Corps, Squadron Training Manager, Cherry Point, North Carolina

Dec. 2016 - June 2018, Dec. 2016 - June 2018

- •Managed the annual training requirements for a Squadron of 205 Marines.
- •Recorded and ensured the execution of weekly training events including Rifle and Pistol Range, Physical Fitness Testing, and Sexual Assault Prevention and Response training.
- •Maintained over 5000 physical and digital records.
- •Received the highest grade possible of Mission Capable during the the biennial Commanding General's Inspection.

United States Marine Corps, Air Support Operations Operator, Okinawa, Japan

June 2013 - Dec. 2016

- •Coordinated over 500 immediate requests for close air support, casualty evacuations, and assault support.
- •Deconflicted 200+ square miles of crowded airspace, preventing the collision of friendly artillery and aircraft.
- •While in a small unit leadership role in the Phillipines, took responsibility for \$100,000+ of military equipment, including radios, vehicles, and classified communications equipment over 5 weeks.
- •Managed Rifle and Pistol Range operations as a Combat Marksmanship Coach.

VOLUNTEERING

NYC Coders, Volunteer Coder

June 2020 - June 2020

Over the course of four days, I worked with over 150 tech professionals and a number of non profits to discuss, plan, and develop tools in support of the Black Lives Matter movement

PROJECTS

Changes June 2020 - June 2020

My team and I developed an MVP in React/Redux and Express/Sequelize for an application that will allow users to efficiently organize around common goals or shared interests and enact change at the local level, through peaceful protest planning, donating to local organizations in that space, or a number of other ways.

Netflix Recommender

July 2020 - Aug. 2020

July 2020 - July 2020

I built a Web Application with a React front end and a Django back end. Using a Netflix global search API, The application allows a User to generate a random movie by genre, and allow that user to leave a detailed review for other users to view. PostGreSQL was used as the database.

ClassHub July 2020 - Aug. 2020

My team and I built a Classroom Collaboration application which allows college students to share notes, schedule study sessions, and leave reviews for classes they've taken, as well as providing both a class calendar and an integrated personal calendar.

Jericho
I built a small chrome extension that I still use to open incognito windows for blogs which are behind temporary paywalls.

EDUCATION

Associate's Degree General Education

State College of Florida Aug. 2019 - June 2020

Code Platoon

14-week intensive Software Development program focused on Python, JavaScript, Django, ReactJS and PostgreSQL

May 2020 - Sept. 2020